嗓子好点了吗
Your throat feel any better?
我为什么要得单核细胞增多症
Oh, why'd I have to get mono?
这病可不是平白无故被叫做"接吻病"的
Well, it's called "The kissing disease" For a reason.
你和麦克斯一定...我还是打住吧
I assume you and max were... I'm going to stop right there.
算你识相
I think that's best.
我去给你倒茶
Make you some tea.
真抱歉
Sorry about this.
我知道你说你家烟熏消毒期间
I know this wasn't what you expected
想来这儿暂住的时候
when you asked to stay here
想象的肯定不是这副情形
While your place was being fumigated.
阿丽克西斯本该跟她妈妈去巴黎的
Alexis was supposed to be going to paris with her mother.
没事
It's fine.
好吧
Mm. Okay. Well...
我去开
I'll get it.
如果你想搬去酒店
If you wanted to stay in a hotel,
-我完全能够理解  -不
I would completely underst-- no.
我哪能因为你女儿病了就撇下你
I'm not gonna leave you just 'cause your daughter's sick.
理查德
Richard.
我会用各种方式补偿你的
I am gonna make this up to you in so many ways.
理查德
Richard.
怎么啦
What?
你前妻驾到
Your ex-wife is here.
-梅瑞狄斯  -妈妈
- Meredith? - Mom?
好啊  小猫猫
Hello, kitten.
你怎么来了
Uh, what...what are you doing here?
阿丽克西斯
Alexis.
我可怜的宝贝
Oh, my poor baby.
你不是去巴黎了吗
Aren't you supposed to be in paris?
哪能不带宝贝闺女
Not without my daughter.
既然你不能去巴黎
And since you can't go to paris,
我就把巴黎带来给你
I'm bringing paris to you...
法式甜馅饼和《甜妞儿》
French pastries and "Funny face."
享受的同时  我会帮你恢复健康
We can enjoy them as I nurse you back to health.
梅瑞狄斯  你怎么...为什么
Meredith, how...why...
为什么拿了这么多行李
Why so much luggage?
真不敢相信你居然
I cannot believe that you are actually
让你的前妻跟你  跟我们一起住
letting your ex-wife stay with you, with us.
那我该怎么办  撵她去酒店吗
What was I supposed to do, stick her in a hotel?
没错
Yes.
她来照顾阿丽克西斯我能理解
Look, I get her taking care of Alexis.
但居然要住你家
But staying at your place?
好了  打住
Okay, wait. Hang on.
我还问你了  "你不介意吧"
I turned to you, I said, "Is it all right with you?"
你说"没事"
And then you said "Yes."
那我要怎么说
What am I supposed to say?
大家都盯着我呢
Everyone is looking at me.
我可不想唱黑脸
I'm not meant to be the bad guy in this case.
得你来
You are.
而且  我都给你使眼色了
Besides, I gave you the look.
-什么眼色  -就是那个眼色
- What look? - The look look.
我犀利的眼神
My look.
别告诉我都四年了
Please don't tell me, after four years,
你还无法领会我的眼神
You don't actually know the look.
你得理解
You gotta understand...
得了吧  我现在不想讨论这个了
You know what? I'm not talking about this right now.
早啊  蕾妮
Good morning, lanie.
这语气不对劲啊  怎么了
Not from the way you sound. What's wrong?
男人真是狗屁不懂
Men are clueless.
所有男人  还是单指卡塞尔
Men or just Castle?
不管你今天过得咋样
Well, no matter how miserable your day is,
肯定比米歇尔·图伊强
it's not as bad as Michelle Twohey's.
她脖子侧面挨了一记冰锥
She took an ice pick to the side of the neck.
米歇尔·图伊
Michelle Twohey,
那个专给权贵人士打离婚官司的律师
the divorce lawyer for the rich and famous?
她不是只替女人打官司吗
Isn't she the one that only represented women?
令很多准前夫闻风丧胆
And strikes fear into the heart of many a soon-to-be ex-husband.
还有别的  我来的时候
There's something else. When I got here,
她手里攥着张纸
she had a piece of paper clutched in her hand
上面有个名字和地址  莱恩
with a name and an address. Ryan.
纸上写的是"R·嘉瑞森"
The name on the paper is "R. Garrison."
地址在斯卡斯戴尔
It's a Scarsdale address,
但不在被害人的通讯录里
but it's not in our victim's contact numbers.
那边有个值夜班的店员
Yo, there's a night clerk around the corner
看见晚上11:45有人逃离现场
who saw a man fleeing the scene at 11:45 p.m.
疑犯飞快地从那边进入了地铁
Suspect ducked into that subway entrance over there.
我们在调摄像头的录像
We're pulling video from the security cameras,
那个店员会给疑犯做描述画像
and the clerk's gonna sit with a sketch artist.
被害人的家人呢
What about the victim's family?
都不在本地
Not anyone local.
她办公室给了我男朋友的电话
Her office gave me the boyfriend's number.
名叫科瑞·弗兰西斯
A guy named Corey Francis.
你们去查查R·嘉瑞森是怎么牵扯进来的
Okay, you guys see how R. Garrison figures into this.
我和卡塞尔去找男朋友谈
Castle and I will take the boyfriend.
科瑞
So, Corey,
你和米歇尔约会多久了
how long had you and Michelle been dating?
不到一个月
Oh, less than a month.
怎么说呢  我们一见面就...
I don't know. We met, we just...
感觉奇妙无比
It was like magic.
你最后和她通话是什么时候
When was the last time you spoke with her?
周末的时候
Over the weekend.
她正在忙一宗离婚案
She was in the middle of a divorce case.
她做这个工作  树敌不少吧
I'm sure in her line of work, she made a lot of enemies.
有什么人来找她麻烦了吗
Was there anyone in particular giving her trouble?
不知道
I don't know.
她的案子都涉及大数额的钱财
Her cases involved big money,
和有头有脸的人物
big egos, but...
但那只是她的工作  她不该遭遇这种事
she was just doing her job. She didn't deserve this.
目击者看到有人
We had a witness who saw somebody
逃离犯罪现场
running away from the crime scene.
你认得出这个人吗
Do you recognize this man?
不  没什么印象
No. He...he doesn't look familiar.
我们在她身上找到一个斯卡斯戴尔的地址
We found a Scarsdale address on her.
你听过R·嘉瑞森这个名字吗
Does the name R. Garrison sound familiar?
没有
No.
我没听她提起过
No, I-I never heard her mention it.
瞧瞧这里啊
Man. Look at this place.
一般般啦
Eh. It's all right.
-说梦话呢  -怎么了
- Are you kidding me? - What?
能有这么漂亮的家
It has always been a dream of mine
一直是我的梦想
to come home to a house like this.
管他什么房子
Screw the house.
能有这么漂亮的女朋友
It's always been a dream of mine...
才一直是我的梦想
to come home to a woman like that.
是啊
Right.
不过等你们认真了起来
Until, of course, things got serious,
你就会甩掉她
which is when you'd dump her
再去找下一个梦中情人
and start looking for your next dream woman.
夫人  我们是纽约警局的
NYPD, ma'am.
我是莱恩警探  这位是埃斯波西托警探
I'm Detective Ryan. This is Detective Esposito.
喊我哈维尔就好
Just call me Javier.
这里有位R·嘉瑞森吗
Is there an R. Garrison here?
有  那是我丈夫罗伯
Yes, that's my husband Rob.
请进
Come on in.
听见没  有老公了
Hear that? "Husband"...
-还是我们的嫌疑人  -好吧
- And suspect. - Yeah.
不  我们没见过
No, we've actually never met.
那你知道她身上怎么会有你的地址和名字吗
Do you have any idea why she had your name and address on her?
我昨晚跟她通话的时候给她的
Well, I gave it to her last night when I spoke with her.
我是一个法务会计师  一般做破产案
I'm a forensic accountant. It's mostly bankruptcies.
但也经常为离婚律师做咨询
But I do a lot of consulting for divorce attorneys.
图伊小姐突然来找我
So Ms. Twohey called me up, out of the blue,
想要见面咨询一些财务问题
and wanted to meet and go over some financial issues.
谁的财务问题  她的吗
Whose financial issues, her own?
这她没说
She didn't say.
但我认得这个名字  也听说过她
But I recognized her name and I knew her reputation,
所以我猜应该是为了她的案子
so I assumed it was about one of her clients.
但是我们的谈话有点奇怪
It was an odd conversation, though.
什么叫奇怪
Odd? How do you mean?
她坚持一定要今天见面
Well, she insisted on meeting today.
所以不管是什么问题
So whatever the issues were,
图伊小姐都急着想解决
Ms. Twohey was a bit frantic about getting them resolved quickly.
如果那次见面是关于客户
Hmm. Look, if that meeting was about a client,
那我们就得查明是谁
then we gotta find out which one.
去她办公室
So head down to her office
看看她手里是什么案子
and see what cases she was working on.
既然米歇尔只有女性客户
And you know what? Since Michelle only represented women,
看看是否有与她对立的丈夫威胁过她
see if any of the men she went up against threatened her.
是啊  一到前妻的问题上
Yeah, men are known to do stupid things
男人就会做傻事
when it comes to their ex-wives.
好的
Okay.
谢谢
Thank you.
我来替你倒吧
Hey. I'll get that for you.
没事  我自己来
That's okay. I got it.
我只想告诉你
So just to let you know,
梅瑞狄斯的事我很抱歉
I'm real sorry about that whole Meredith thing,
但我会解决的
But I am going to... take care of it.
好的  我们就到
Yeah. Okay. We'll be right there.
蕾妮叫我们去
Lanie's got something for us.
你去吧  我去处理...
You go deal with that. I'm gonna go deal with...
那件事
The other thing.
我搞得定
Take care of it.
不  该由你去搞定
No. You've gotta take care of it.
这可是梅瑞狄斯啊
This is Meredith we're talking about--
每次来纽约卡塞尔都会跟她滚床单的
The deep-fried twinkie that Castle has ex-sex with
油炸奶糕[外号出自第一季]
whenever she rolls into town.
蕾妮
Lanie.
我信任他
Look, I trust him.
他不会跟她滚床单的
He's not gonna have sex with her.
好吧
Fine.
就算跟滚床单无关
Let's say it isn't about sex.
这是个界限问题
It's about boundaries.
梅瑞狄斯这是在标记领地呢
Meredith is marking her territory.
你不能让她随心所欲的来去
You can't just let her waltz in and out whenever she pleases.
他没办法  阿丽克西斯病了
He's in a catch-22. Alexis is sick--
那又怎么样
Doesn't matter.
这可是战争  你说现在是谁在节节败退
This is a war, girl, and guess who's losing.
我不知道
I don't know.
或许你是对的
Maybe you're right.
什么叫或许  我必须是对的
Maybe I'm right? Of course I'm right.
蕾妮  我过来不是为了探讨这个
Lanie, I didn't come down here to talk about this.
你说你找到了跟案子有关的东西
You said that you have something case related.
是的  想听点好消息吗
Yes. Are you ready for some good news now?
那好啊
That would be nice.
我分析了被害人的衣物
I processed the victim's clothing
找到了另一人的血迹
and found trace amounts of someone else's blood
就在她的夹克扣子上
on her jacket button.
那么凶手可能在行凶时把自己割伤了
Which means our killer could've gotten cut during the attack.
这会儿在查DNA呢
I'm running D.N.A. now.
有发现会告诉你
I'll call you when I got something.
谢谢
Thank you.
米歇尔律所的所有员工
So each one of Michelle's employees at her law firm
都有不在场证据
alibied out.
但他们都说她过去几周举止奇怪
But they all said she'd been acting odd during the past few weeks.
他们觉得是因为一件案子
They assumed it had to do with a case.
什么案子
Which case?
选一个吧
Pick one.
为你介绍曼哈顿的富豪们
Introducing the wealthy men of Manhattan.
在离婚案中  米歇尔是
Michelle represented all their wives
他们妻子的律师
in ongoing divorces,
有一些愤怒的丈夫威胁过她
And some of these angry husbands had threatened her.
唯一的问题是  他们的外貌都和素描不符
The only problem is, none of 'em matched our sketch.
也许是因为某人
Maybe that's because one of them
雇佣了这位神秘男来谋杀米歇尔
hired our mystery man to kill Michelle.
但必须找到神秘男才能知道到底是谁雇了他
But we won't know which one until we find this guy.
我找到了
And I just did.
在地铁的监控录像里
On the subway security video,
我看见嫌疑犯刷地铁卡
I saw our suspect swipe his M.T.A. Card.
他是用信用卡买的
He used a credit card to buy it.
赫曼·波及尤
Herman Poquille.
几起入室盗窃案和加重攻击罪
A few B&Es, aggravated assault,
哎呦  还有几次试图谋杀呢
Oh, and several attempted murders.
恭喜  你终于成功了
Congratulations. You finally succeeded.
问题是  我们弄不明白
Only thing is, we can't figure out
你为什么要杀图伊女士
why you'd want to kill Ms. Twohey.
没偷钱包
Purse wasn't stolen.
没开走汽车  你为什么要杀害她
The car wasn't jacked. So why'd you want to kill her?
我没杀她  事情不是你们想的那样
I didn't kill her. It's not what you think.
得了吧  赫曼
Come on, Herman.
你可以坦白一切  有人雇了你
You can talk to us. Someone hired you.
对啊  她雇的
Yeah, she did.
我说了  事情不是你们想的那样
Like I said. It's not what you think.
我以前为米歇尔工作
I used to work for Michelle.
做什么
Doing what?
拍照
Photographer.
拍下丈夫偷情之类的照片
Shots of husbands cheating on their wives, stuff like that.
这还是无法解释
That still doesn't explain
你当时在犯罪现场做什么
what you were doing at the crime scene.
听着
Look,
不久前我搞砸了一次任务
I botched an assignment a while ago,
于是米歇尔炒了我
and Michelle fired me.
突然  她又给我打电话
Then all of a sudden, she's calling me,
让我帮她接个大活儿
asking me for my help on some big job.
什么大活儿
What big job?
她没说
She didn't say.
她说她在回家的路上
She said she was heading home
会在地铁站旁边等我
and would wait for me near the subway.
我到的时候  她已经死了
By the time I got there, she was dead.
我不想和谋杀案扯上关系  所以就逃跑了
I didn't want to get mixed up in a murder, so I ran.
-你们不信我吗  -不信
- You don't believe me? - Mnh-mnh.
去看我手机上的短信吧
Check the texts on my phone.
都有呢
It's all there.
我查看了赫曼的手机
So I went through Herman's phone,
他没撒谎
and he wasn't lying.
米歇尔想雇他拍照片
Michelle wanted to hire him to take photos,
看上去她很绝望
and she seemed pretty desperate.
赫曼不想接这份活
Herman didn't want to take the job,
一直回复她"不行"
and he kept texting her "No."
但她最后总算靠视频说服了他
But she seemed to finally win him over with this.
赫曼
Okay, Herman.
我的短信没有让你改变主意
My texts aren't changing your mind,
也许这段视频能
so maybe this will.
看着我  我在求你
Look at me. I'm pleading.
我遇上了大麻烦  需要你
I have a huge problem, and I need you
和你的照相机帮我最后一个忙
and that camera of yours for one last job.
求你了
Please.
性命攸关
A life hangs in the balance.
"A life hangs in the balance"?
她到底要拍谁的照片
What the hell did she need a photo of?
好啊
Hi there.
抓到凶手了吗
Did you catch the killer already?
还没有  阿丽克西斯怎么样了
Uh, no. Not yet. How's Alexis?
她还在睡觉  但我要端着热汤去叫醒她
Mm, sleeping, but I'm gonna wake her with some soup.
你要吗
Want some?
不用了  谢谢
Oh. Um, no, thanks.
梅瑞狄斯
Listen, Meredith,
关于你住这里的事
about you staying here--
再次感谢  理查德
Thanks again, Richard.
这对我来说真是意义重大
I can't tell you how much this means to me.
好吧
Yeah.
-只是  贝克特和我  -都是好人
- It's just... Beckett and I... - Are wonderful.
看到你们俩的
It's so refreshing to see
关系如此稳定  我真是太开心了
how secure you two are in your relationship.
大部分女人都会不满
You know, most women would take issue with an ex-wife
男朋友和前女友住一起
staying with their boyfriend.
但凯特·贝克特不一样  她通情达理
But not Kate Beckett. She gets it.
是啊  凯特通情达理
Yeah. Kate gets it.
问题是  梅瑞狄斯  我...
Um, here's the thing, Meredith, I...
我懂
I know.
而且...
And...
要我承认这点很不容易
It isn't easy for me to admit...
但我并不是个好妈妈
I haven't been the best of mothers.
我错过了我们女儿的太多生活
I've missed so much of our daughter's life.
你现在让我住在这里
So the fact that you're letting me be here now
照顾生病的阿丽克西斯
for Alexis during her time of need,
理查德  我永远不会忘记的
Richard, I'll never, ever forget this.
贝克特也忘不了
Neither will Beckett.
怎么样
Well?
什么怎么样
Well, what?
那事啊
Oh, that.
我还在处理
Still working on that.
寻找杀害米歇尔·图伊的凶手
What about, uh, any progress
有什么进展吗
on finding Michelle Twohey's killer?
还没有
No, not yet.
我们还在核对前夫们的不在场证明
We're still checking on the ex-husbands' alibis.
各位
Hey, guys.
我觉得我们该换个思路
Uh... I think we might have our theory backwards.
如果杀害图伊女士的
What if it wasn't an angry ex-husband
不是愤怒的丈夫呢
that killed Ms. Twohey?
也可能是前妻干的
What if it was an ex-wife?
麻烦的前妻
Oh, wow. A troublesome ex-wife?
想象一下吧
Imagine that.
你觉得是她的客户杀了她
So you think one of her clients killed her?
蕾妮查到了
Uh, well, Lanie got a hit
米歇尔外套上的血迹
on the blood found on Michelle's jacket.
是萨曼莎·沃斯的
It belongs to a Samantha Voss.
她在犯罪系统里有在洛杉矶酒驾的记录
She's in the system due to a D.U.I. Arrest in Los Angeles.
她对米歇尔不满吗
Did she have a grievance with Michelle?
我觉得是  米歇尔被谋杀的那天早上
Oh, I'd say so. The morning of Michelle's murder,
一名法官宣判了萨曼莎
a judge came down with a ruling
备受争议的离婚案的裁决
in Samantha's contentious divorce case.
她的损失可大了
She lost big.
有多大
How big is big?
她失掉了上东区的公寓
Uh, upper east side apartment big.
豪车  游艇
Cars and boats big.
还有百万资产的一半
Half of her multimillion-dollar net worth big.
确实很大啊
That's big.
而且判决结束后  萨曼莎愤然离场
Especially when Samantha went off on a courtroom tirade,
指责米歇尔搞砸了她的案子
accusing Michelle of screwing up her case.
她身上当然有我的血
Of course my blood was on her.
她把我的离婚案搞得一团糟
Michelle completely mishandled my divorce.
我气疯了  我们动起手来
I was furious. Our spat became physical,
她外套上的金属扣子割到了我的手
And I cut my hand on one of her metal jacket buttons.
但我可没杀她
But I didn't kill her.
-沃斯太太  -沃斯太太已经死了
- Mrs. Voss... - Mrs. Voss is dead.
我单身了  是彼得曼小姐  谢谢
I'm back to Ms. Peterman now, thank you.
别  别  别
Oh, no, no, no, no, no.
瓷器不用打包
Don't pack the china.
它们跟了我前夫
That stays with my ex now.
那个混蛋
The jackhole.
彼得曼小姐  昨晚十点到凌晨一点
Ms. Peterman, where were you last night
你人在哪里
between 10:00 and 1:00?
我在参加一个慈善拍卖会
I was at a charity auction,
是由我主持的
which I chair,
直到两点才结束
until 2:00 a.m.
有一百多人能为我作证呢
There are over a hundred donors who can vouch for that.
想查就查吧
Just check it out if you'd like.
你可能没杀米歇尔
Well, you may not have killed Michelle,
但你确实毁了一幅珍贵的油画
but you certainly murdered that original Zaozirny.
我可用不着靠杀人来报仇
I don't have to kill to get revenge.
报复我前夫的方法多了去了
Not when there's so many other ways to get back at my ex.
悲哀啊
Shame.
那盘子可是搭配这些的关键
That platter really tied the set together.
彼得曼小姐  如果你不再乱摔东西的话
Ms. Peterman, if you could just refrain from destroying anything else,
你也许能帮上点忙
you actually might be of some help.
米歇尔有没有什么异常表现呢
Now did Michelle say or do anything out of the ordinary?
我跟你说啊
Ooh, well, let me tell you,
那个女人肯定有什么不对劲的地方
something was sure as hell wrong in that woman's life,
过去的一个月里
because for the past month,
她总是心神不宁
she was just distracted.
为什么心神不宁
Distracted by what?
我的案子让她找不到头绪
She got lost in the details of my case
根本找不到好法子来解决呗
that had absolutely no bearing on securing a better settlement,
更别提她的私人问题了
and don't even get me started on her personal problems.
什么私人问题
What do you mean, her personal problems?
大侦探  我只是个客户  不是她闺蜜
Detective, I was her client, not her B.F.F.
她的私事我不清楚
I don't know.
不过我可以告诉你
Although I can tell you,
昨天她出庭来迟了
yesterday she came to court late
而且她还
and she was...
哭了
crying.
她说明原因了吗
Did she tell you why?
说了  她说她那天有一堆麻烦的
Yes. She said that she was having messy personal issues.
私人问题
that day.
你对我收藏的名画做了什么
What did you do to my Zaozirny?
真欢乐啊  我的前夫回家了
Oh, joy. My ex is home.
沃尔特  沃尔特  沃尔特
Walter, Walter, Walter.
进来啊  我们有伴了  打个招呼吧
Come in. We have company. Say hello.
你这个贱人
You bitch.
错了  亲爱的
No, dear.
你买回家跟你乱搞的女人才是贱人
The bitch is the skank you paid to have sex with you.
沃尔特  不要
Walter, no.
不要  沃尔特  不要
No, walter. No, walter!
谁再摔东西
Next person to break anything
谁就蹲监狱
goes to jail.
都是你的错
This is all your fault.
但老娘值了
And it was so worth it.
地狱烈焰也难敌女人怒火啊
Hell hath no fury.
你跟你前妻们也这样吗
Did it ever get that bad with either of your exes?
不不  我们都是和平分手的
No, no. Both my divorces were amicable.
和平过头了吧
Yeah, a little too amicable.
米歇尔·图伊有心事
So something was going on with Michelle Twohey.
她丧命的那一天早晨
On the morning of her death,
她出庭迟到  还哭了
she arrived to court late and she had been crying.
她到底去哪了
So where was she coming from?
她的消费记录显示
Well, according to her financials,
出庭之前  她去咖啡馆吃了早餐
she paid for breakfast at a cafe right before court,
说不定那里的人会有线索
so maybe someone there will let us know what was so upsetting.
哥们
Bro.
这是咋回事
What was that?
什么咋回事
What was what?
你的女朋友刚刚
Your girlfriend just uttered
讥讽了你的前妻
a sarcastic remark about your ex-wife,
你还问是咋回事
and all you're gonna say is "What was what?"
没什么大不了的
Oh, that was nothing.
-抓紧的  -说说吧
- Spit it out. - Tell us.
好吧  你们知道的
Uh, okay. Uh, as you know...
贝克特在她的房子烟熏消毒期间
Beckett is staying at the loft
住在我家
while her place is getting fumigated.
阿丽克西斯抱病在家  结果梅瑞狄斯出现了
Alexis is home sick as well. And then Meredith showed up,
她说她想住我家
and she said she wanted to stay in the loft.
然后你拒绝了
And you said no.
请告诉我  你拒绝了
Tell me you said no.
真的假的
Really?
你都有女朋友了  还让前妻跟你住吗
Letting an ex stay with you when you're with someone else?
你这简直是火上浇油啊
That's like throwing gasoline on fireworks.
我说伙计们  没那么糟糕吧
Come on. Guys, it... it's not that bad.
卡塞尔  你现在的处境
Castle, you are on the edge
非常非常危险啊  老兄
of a very, very steep cliff, my friend.
不赶快想法子解决的话
And if you don't do something about it quick...
咖啡馆老板记得米歇尔
So the cafe owner remembers Michelle having an argument
当时在跟一位高大帅气  30多岁  浅棕发色
with a tall, good-looking man, mid-30s, light brown hair,
蓝眼睛的男人争吵
and blue eyes.
是她的男朋友科瑞·弗兰西斯吗
Her boyfriend Corey Francis?
他不是说周末后就没见过米歇尔吗
I thought he said he hadn't seen Michelle since the weekend.
他为什么要说谎
Now why would he lie?
他在隐瞒什么
Looks like he's hiding something.
把他找来问问看
Let's bring him down here and find out what?
是的  能不能再送一些
Yes, and if you could have
草莓和香槟上去备着
some strawberries and champagne sent up there waiting.
太棒了
Perfect.
塞德里克  我欠你人情  谢了
Cedric, I owe you. Thank you.
米歇尔跟男朋友吵了一架
Michelle fights with her boyfriend,
然后跟一位会计约好了见面
she sets up a meeting with an accountant,
还雇了一个摄影师
and then she hires a photographer.
她到底遇上什么事了
What the hell was she into?
不知道
I don't know.
不如我们今晚在四季酒店的超大按摩浴缸里
But why don't we discuss it tonight in our
讨论这个问题吧
oversized Jacuzzi at the Four Seasons,
我刚在那里预定了大使套房
where I just booked us the ambassador suite.
为什么
Why would you do that?
因为你家还在烟熏消毒
Because your place is still being fumigated,
我家又人满为患
and my loft is overrun with redheads.
我就想  我们何不去享受一番呢
So I thought, why not just go and enjoy ourselves?
科瑞·弗兰西斯在哪
You guys, where's Corey Francis?
有麻烦了
Well, we got a problem.
他失踪了
He's disappeared.
他的手机也无法接通
His cell has been disconnected,
地址是假的  连名字也是捏造的
His address is bogus. So's his name.
死者交往的对象根本不存在
The guy that our victim was dating doesn't exist?
更糟的是  根本没法找到他
What's worse, we have no way of finding him.
不  等等
No. Wait.
他戴着戒指
He was wearing a ring.
班戒  校戒  上面是"纽约"什么的
Class ring. College ring. A "New york" something.
对  红色戒指  上面刻了个大教堂
Uh, yeah, it was, uh, red with a cathedral imprinted on it.
纽约大学
The University of New York.
可能是他假身份的道具
Might be part of his cover identity.
得了吧
Come...
纽约大学  拜托
University of New York? Come on.
如果你想选个掩饰的身份
If you were gonna pick a cover identity,
怎么不选个更好的
wouldn't you pick a better school than U...
你是纽约大学毕业的
University of New York?
对
Yeah.
我们可以用年鉴来查明他的身份
You know, we can I.D. him using the yearbooks.
他三十多岁  我们不如彻查
He's in mid-30s, so why don't we grab
1996年那几年所有大学图书馆的资料吧
everything from the university library from '96 and on?
那地方可有点偏僻
Oh, well, that's, uh, upstate.
-我们明早去查  -对
- We'll have it for you in the morning. - Yeah.
不行
No.
什么不行
No what?
不去四季酒店
No on the Four Seasons.
如果有人要去宾馆  那也该是梅瑞狄斯
If anyone should be sent to a hotel, it's Meredith.
我试过了  只是...
Well, I tried. It just--
让她陪着阿丽克西斯对她来说意义重大
It means so much to her to be there for Alexis,
要是把她赶去宾馆住
and, ah, it just seemed heartless
就太冷血无情了
to kick her out and send her to a hotel.
是吗  卡塞尔  你刚才还想打发我去宾馆呢
Really, Castle? 'cause you just tried sending me to one.
不  那是因为
No, but that was because...
没有因为了
But nothing.
住嘴  猫咪  我们回家
Button up, kitten. We're going home.
真香啊  我能喝一杯吗
That smells delicious. Can I have a cup?
我是给卡塞尔煮的
I... was just making that for Castle.
不过  好吧  给
But, yeah, here.
阿丽克西斯怎么样
So how is Alexis?
她在睡觉  她总是在睡觉
She's asleep. She's always asleep.
我爱她  不过说实话
I love her, but with mono,
她这人其实挺无聊的
she's a bit of a bore.
你和里奇怎么样
So you and Rick...
对  我和里奇
Yes. Me and Rick.
那...
So...
话说
You know, uh,
你还是把裤子穿上吧
you might want to put some pants on.
为什么  我又不出去
Why? It's not like I'm going anywhere.
你们早啊
Hey, you two.
怎么了
What's going on?
没什么  只是在煮咖啡
Nothing. Just making coffee.
给  这杯给你
Here. This is for you.
谢谢
Oh, thank you.
里面是什么  你是不是加了...
What is in this? Did you add...
-肉豆蔻  -肉豆蔻
- Nutmeg? - Nutmeg.
肉豆蔻
Nutmeg?
里奇每次熬夜
Whenever Rick pulled all-nighters,
我都会给他在咖啡里洒肉豆蔻
I'd sprinkle nutmeg in his coffee.
后劲更足  你想试试吗
Gave it an extra kick. You want to try?
不  谢了
Uh, no, thanks.
我觉得今天早上后劲已经够足了
I think I've had enough kick for one morning.
我去上班了
I will be at work.
听着
Listen, um...
咖啡的事
That whole coffee thing,
梅瑞狄斯没有恶意
Meredith didn't mean anything by that.
她只是想更周到些
She's just trying to be thoughtful.
那是当然
I'm sure she was.
你没生气
So you're not mad?
生什么气
About what?
气你前妻在你家和你家人相处
About how comfortable your ex-wife is in your home
有多和睦吗
and with your family,
气她对你的事了如指掌  而我却一无所知吗
how she seems to know things about you that I don't know?
我有什么好气的
Why would I be upset?
你看  这就是我想住在四季酒店的原因
Okay, see, this is why I wanted to stay at the Four Seasons,
这样你就不用面对这些事了
So you wouldn't have to deal with this.
卡塞尔  我本来就不该面对这些事
Castle, I shouldn't have to deal with this
因为你本该拒绝她的
because you should've said no.
是  可我没有  现在我又骑虎难下
Yes, but I didn't, and now I can't.
我知道了  我会...
I know. I'll...
我会让阿丽克西斯和梅瑞狄斯去四季酒店
I'll send Alexis and Meredith to the Four Seasons.
只要雇个值班医生就行了
I'll just hire a concierge doctor.
不  卡塞尔  我不是小孩子  好吗
No. Castle, I am a big girl, okay?
我能体谅你前妻的心情
I can be in the same place as your ex-wife.
那你不走吗
So you'll stay?
对  当然
Yeah. Sure.
我会忍受她半裸着走来走去
I'll just be subjected to her parading around half naked.
我怎么说都没用了  是吧
Oh. Okay. I can't win, can I?
对  都是你的错
Oh, right. Because this is all about you.
你让这事...
Well, you made it...
如果我...
If I...
好吧  知道吗  你说得对
Okay, you know what? You're right.
你说得太对了
You are absolutely right.
我们只需要再忍几天和我疯狂的前妻
All we have to do is get through the next few days
共处的日子
with my crazy ex-wife.
好吗
What do you say?
诺亚[发音近似"不"]
Noah.
不
No?
不是"不"  是诺亚·加斯伍德
No, not "No." Noah Kesswood.
科瑞·弗兰西斯实际上是...
Corey Francis is really...
诺亚·加斯伍德
Noah Kesswood.
陆军情报部门的前任官员
Former officer in the army's military intelligence corps.
前任军情官员
Former military intelligence?
诺亚用假身份  开始和米歇尔交往
Noah uses a fake identity, starts dating Michelle,
在她遇害后便失踪了
and then he disappears just after she's killed?
《单身汉》混搭《国土安全》啊
It's "The bachelor" meets "Homeland."
不管他的目的是什么  唯一的线索是
Whatever he was up to, the only trace of him I could find
他的名下登记了一家转租公司
is a loan-out corporation registered in his name.
而且最近公司账户很活跃
And there's been a lot of recent activity.
收到了有几笔大额电汇
Several large wire transfers were made
都是从本地本柯舒律所汇入
from a local law firm-- Benedict, Cole and Schuster.
时间大概是从
Those payments began around the time that
诺亚与米歇尔约会开始
Noah started dating Michelle.
是不是觉得是有人雇了诺亚监视她
Think someone was paying Noah to spy on her?
米歇尔接的案子赚来的钱都是七位数
Well, Michelle's cases had outcomes in the millions.
没准是其他律师眼红呢
Maybe an opposing lawyer was angling for an advantage.
如果米歇尔发现自己被监视
If Michelle found out that she was being spied on,
那个律师就会面临违反职业道德的控诉
then that lawyer would face an ethics violation
以及被吊销执照
and disbarment.
足够让他绝望到花钱
It might have made him desperate enough to pay Noah
让诺亚杀了米歇尔来解决问题
to kill Michelle to make the problem go away.
有可能  最好的方法是
It is possible, but the best way to find out
找到那个付钱的律师
is to track down the lawyer that authorized those payments.
给你纸巾
Here. There's the napkins.
舒斯特先生
Mr. Schuster.
你的助理说能在这找到你
Your office said we'd find you down here.
我是埃斯波西托警探
I'm Detective Esposito.
这是我搭档  莱恩警探
This is my partner, Detective Ryan.
我猜你们不是来买热狗的吧
I'm guessing you're not here for the hot dogs.
我们想问几个关于诺亚·加斯伍德的问题
We'd like you to come answer some questions about Noah Kesswood.
你们应该知道我是个刑事律师
I'm sure you know I'm a criminal attorney
清楚自己的权利
who's very aware of his rights.
我不会跟你们回警局
I'm not going anywhere.
可以在这儿谈
Ah. Then we can talk here.
你们如果想讨论把肉做成圆管状的优点
You want to discuss the virtues of processed meat in tube form?
我奉陪
Fine.
否则你们还是别浪费时间了
Otherwise, you're wasting your time.
不如谈谈你给诺亚·加斯伍德
How about we discuss the wire transfers
电汇的那些钱吧
you made to Noah Kesswood,
他是杀害米歇尔·图伊的嫌疑人
a suspect in the murder of Michelle Twohey?
省省你们的鹅肝  烧鸭
Save your foie gras, your roast duck,
和酒闷仔鸡吧
your coq au vin.
对我来说  最好吃的是纽约街头的热狗
For me, fine dining is a New York hot dog.
舒斯特先生  最后一笔电汇的金额是一万美元
Mr. Schuster, we know the last transfer was for 10 grand,
在米歇尔被害那天早上汇出
sent the morning Michelle was murdered.
像是你们律所花钱雇诺亚铲除同行
Sounds like your law firm paid Noah to kill a fellow attorney.
太荒唐了
That's ridiculous.
也许吧  但是如果我们把证据串在一起
Maybe, but when we connect the dots,
你觉得媒体也会觉得荒唐吗
do you think the media will see it that way?
好吧
Okay.
接下来的事情是这样的  两位警探
Here's what's gonna happen, detectives.
你们会发现我受客户委托雇佣诺亚
You're gonna find out that I was instructed by a client
帮他处理事情
to pay Noah Kesswood for his service.
你们会问处理什么事
You're gonna ask what that service was.
我会说"我不知道"
I'm gonna say, "I don't know."
然后你们会很爷们地要我说出客户的名字
Then you're gonna puff up and demand the name of my client,
我会这样回应"这是保密信息
to which I'll reply, "That's privileged information.
自己玩儿蛋去吧"
Kindly go screw yourselves."
买个热狗吧  好吃极了
Have a hot dog, boys. They're delicious.
舒斯特也许有当事人保密特权
Mr. Schuster may have attorney-client privilege,
但是他的客户名字是公开的
but who he represents is a matter of public record.
所以我查看了他律所
So I looked back into his law firm's cases
五年内的案子
for the past five years.
结果发现舒斯特代理过比利·派珀
Turns out Schuster represented Billy Piper.
你们还记得那事儿吧
You guys remember the story, right?
当然  新闻上播了好几个月
Yeah, it was all over the news for months.
著名高尔夫职业选手要离婚
Famous pro golfer getting a divorce
为了挽救婚姻
takes a boating trip to the Caribbean
带着老婆去加勒比海航海旅行
to work on his marriage...
只是他老婆再也没能上岸
Only his wife never makes it back to shore.
比利声称他俩喝醉了
Billy claimed that the two of them were drinking,
他妻子是意外落海
and his wife accidentally fell off of the boat.
所有人都认为这是谋杀
Everyone assumed it was murder.
但是联调局没有足够的证据起诉他
But the feds never had enough to indict him.
的确
Indeed.
这和我们的死者有什么关系呢
So what does any of this have to do with our victim?
三年前
Three years ago,
米歇尔的一个客户从船上消失了
Michelle had a client who disappeared from her boat.
那个客户
That client...
就是莉安娜·派珀
was Leann Piper.
比利·派珀的老婆
Billy Piper's wife?
这不可能是巧合
That can't be a coincidence.
我也是这么想的
I don't think it was.
我在米歇尔的电脑上
In fact, I found a file...
找到了一个文件
on Michelle's computer that showed that
证明她在被害前一月在调查莉安娜·派珀的谋杀
she'd been looking into Leann Piper's murder for the past month.
等一下
Wait a minute.
如果米歇尔发现是比利杀害了他老婆
What if Michelle figured out how Billy killed his wife?
你是说找到了确凿证据吗
You mean by finding actual evidence?
是的  比利想要阻止
Right. Then the only way...
证据公开的唯一方法就是
Billy could stop that proof from coming out...
杀了米歇尔
Was to have Michelle killed.
那是我最引以为傲的奖杯
That's my pride and joy.
2002年在奥古斯塔赢的
Won it in Augusta in '02.
你打出老鹰球获胜
You eagled for the win.
你没记错
That's right.
你们要喝点什么吗
Can I get either of you two a drink?
我们不是来串门的  派珀先生
This isn't a social visit, Mr. Piper.
我们来询问关于米歇尔·图伊的事
We're here to talk to you about Michelle Twohey.
米歇尔 谁
Michelle who-ey?
抱歉  我没听过这个人
Sorry. It doesn't sound familiar.
真是奇怪  你竟然没听过你已故妻子的离婚律师
It's odd that you don't remember your late wife's divorce lawyer.
你知道这位律师死了吗
Did you know that she'd turned up dead?
之所以来问你是因为一个月前
The reason I'm asking is because she visited you
她来找过你
about a month ago.
不记得她来过
Hmm. Don't recall any visits.
你确定吗
You sure about that?
那之后你就雇了诺亚·加斯伍德
It was right after that visit you hired Noah Kesswood.
诺亚·加斯伍德是谁
Who's Noah Kesswood?
你雇来监视她的人
The man that you paid to spy on her.
结果她就死了
And then she winds up dead.
你不觉得这很可疑吗
That's awfully suspicious, don't you think?
你们这些警察啊
You people.
有人死了
Somebody dies,
就来问我
question Billy.
这也不能怪我们
Well, can you blame us,
特别是在你老婆那件事之后
especially after what happened with your wife?
行了
Okay.
我们来谈谈我老婆
Let's talk about what happened to my wife.
莉安娜起草了离婚协议  我努力挽回
Leann files for divorce so I fight her on it,
因为在我看来  婚姻是神圣的
because where I'm from, marriage is sacred.
所以莉安娜和我决定跟往常一样
So Leann and I decide to go for a boat ride,
去航海旅行
like the old days,
但此举非但没挽回我们的爱情
but instead of recapturing our magic,
莉安娜还醉酒失足掉到海里
Leann got drunk and fell into the ocean.
我怎么就成了恶人了呢
So why am I the bad guy?
这么说你是受害者
Oh, so you're the victim here?
我当然是
You bet your ass, I am.
我失去了广告代言和社会地位
I lost my endorsements and my status.
我的家人也不再理我了
My own family wants nothing to do with me.
有意思的是
Interesting.
你的"失物清单"里
On the list of things you lost,
没有你老婆
you didn't include your wife.
她从来都不是我的最爱
She never was my favorite trophy.
你们也该滚蛋了
Now why don't you two get the hell out of my home?
肯定是比利干的
Well, Billy did it.
他为了保住他的钱杀了他老婆
He killed his wife to keep his money,
当米歇尔发现证据后又杀了米歇尔
Then had Michelle murdered when she found evidence of it.
唯一的问题是怎么证明
Only how do we prove it?
所有的线索都指向诺亚
Well, all roads lead to Noah.
所以如果我们能抓到他
So if we can catch him,
就可以让他指正比利
we'll get him to turn on Billy.
好办法
Perfect.
只是我们找不到他
Only we don't have any way of finding him.
事实上找得到
Actually, we do.
原来比利家大楼的停车场
Turns out the garage at Billy's building
有自动泊车系统
has an automated valet system.
经理找出了当时诺亚
The manager was able to pull up the records
在那儿停车的记录
of when Noah parked there,
我们得到了他的车牌号
and we got his license number.
那辆车属于一个车队
The car belongs to a fleet of vehicles
而车队是注册在一家医药公司名下
that's registered to a pharmaceutical company.
诺亚是那儿的员工吗
Was Noah an employee there?
不  他跟那儿没关系
No, he has no affiliation.
你们继续查下去
All right. You guys keep digging.
这之间一定有什么联系
There's gotta be a connection somewhere.
喂
Hello.
你好
Hey.
是的  梅瑞狄斯  卡塞尔在这儿
Uh, yeah, Meredith. Yeah, Castle's right here.
你说什么
I'm sorry. What?
你找我
You want to talk to me?
对
Uh, yeah.
不
No.
好
Okay.
Fine.
她找你干嘛
What did she want?
她约我晚上吃饭
She asked me to dinner tonight.
就我们俩
Just the two of us.
吃晚饭
To dinner?
你还同意了  你怎么能同意呢
And you said yes? How could you say yes?
你不也同意了让她住你那儿吗
Same way you did when she asked to stay with you.
再说了  卡塞尔  要是我拒绝
Besides, Castle, if said no,
不是显得我不自信吗
that would've made me look insecure.
真的很糟糕吗
Is this as bad as it seems?
不  是非常糟糕  非常非常糟糕
No. It's much worse. Much, much worse.
好吧  先打住
No. Okay, hang on.
我们先冷静一下
Let's... take a step back from this,
然后再想一下
and let's just think about it.
只是一顿晚餐而已
Just dinner.
你前妻
Just dinner between
和你新女友共进的一顿晚餐
your ex-wife and your new girlfriend.
你死定了
That's deadly.
卡塞尔  你有两个世界
Castle, you have two worlds.
两个
Two.
现在  它们相遇了
Right now, they're both coming together.
碰撞时会发生什么呢
Uh-oh. What happens when worlds collide?
砰
Boom.
你们俩打住
Okay, guys.
扯远了
You are taking this a little too far.
卡塞尔
Castle.
-梅瑞狄斯了解你  -那又怎样
- Meredith knows things about you. - So?
-怎样  -怎样
- So? - So?
有没有什么事是她知道
So is there anything Meredith knows
而你又不想让贝克特知道的
that you don't want Beckett to know?
-砰  -两个世界碰撞了
- Boom. - Two worlds colliding.
我称赞过你写字很漂亮吗
Have I told you how lovely your penmanship is?
字体那么有爱  真想再看看
The font is just so friendly. I just look forward to seeing it.
卡塞尔  怎么了
Castle, what is it?
我想确认你想要跟梅瑞狄斯
I just want to make sure you want to go to dinner
一起吃晚餐
with Meredith.
别忘了  她比较疯狂
Remember... she's a little crazy.
还很抓马
And of course, dramatic. Ew.
组合起来就是"疯马"
Miserable combination.
你在担心什么
What are you so worried about?
不过是你熟悉的两个人
I mean, it's just two people that you've been intimate with
在一起交流一下
coming together, comparing notes.
交流一下
Comparing notes.
交流什么
What notes?
我认真的  交流什么
Seriously, though. What notes?
埃斯波  找到诺亚的线索了吗
Hey, Espo. What do you got on Noah?
谢了
Thanks.
我刚刚跟那家医药公司的
I just got off with the vice president
副董事长见过面
from that pharmaceutical company.
你猜他是哪所大学毕业的  纽约大学
Guess where he went to college? University of New York.
再次抱歉
Sorry about that.
他不仅同意让诺亚使用那辆车
Not only was he giving Noah access to that company car,
还同意让诺亚在这段时间
but he's also been letting him
跟他住在一起
stay with him for the past month.
把他带回来
Okay, pick him up.
砰
Boom.
就是他
There he is.
诺亚·加斯伍德  纽约警察  过来
Noah Kesswood. NYPD. Come here.
真的有那么疼吗
That hurt as much as it looked?
很好
Good.
你现在被逮捕了
And now you're under arrest.
看看他
Look at him.
一点儿也不像我昨天见到的那个
Nothing like the devastated boyfriend
伤心憔悴的男朋友
that I met yesterday.
诺亚
Noah.
你挺厉害的  伙计
You're good, man.
但还不够厉害
But you're not that good.
好了  别浪费时间了
All right, let's not waste any time.
我们知道比利雇你去监视米歇尔
We know that Billy hired you to spy on Michelle
看她是否掌握了他杀妻的证据
to see if she had any proof that he killed his wife.
当你发现她确实有证据时
And when you discovered she did,
你服从了比利的命令
on Billy's orders,
把冰锥插进了她的脖子
you put an ice pick through her neck.
我没杀米歇尔
I didn't kill Michelle.
我不相信你
I don't believe you.
不用你信
You don't have to.
米歇尔遇害时
See, while Michelle was being shish kebabed,
我正赶着去纽约大学
I was all the way up at the university of New York,
看母校对西弗吉尼亚的比赛
watching my alma mater play West Virginia.
对了  我们赢了
We won, by the way.
野马队加油
Go, Broncos.
如果你没有杀她
If you didn't kill her,
你为何费这么大力气玩失踪
why'd you work so hard to disappear?
警探
Hey, detective...
你请我喝瓶汽水如何
What do you say you buy me a soda, hmm?
你说什么
Excuse me?
不是你
Not you.
说你呢
You.
听着  我是做情报工作的
All right, look, I deal in intelligence,
不是谋杀  从没杀过人
not murder, never murder.
你想知道真相吗
You want the truth?
好吧  告诉你  不收费
Okay, here it is free of charge.
比利·派珀非常多疑
Billy Piper's absolutely paranoid.
当米歇尔跑来
So when Michelle came around asking questions
问那晚在船上的事
about that night on the boat,
他完全慌了
he went into full-on panic mode.
他认为她要报复他
Figured she probably had a vendetta against him,
想让他因谋杀她的客户而坐牢
wanted him in jail for murdering her client.
事实上  他想的没错
Reality is, he was probably right.
她说她离查明船上究竟发生了什么
She said she was close, very close,
已经非常非常接近了
to finding out what really happened on that boat.
-你指的是确凿的证据吗  -也许吧
- Are we talking actual evidence? - Maybe.
她当时正在缉毒局的纽约办公室
She was gathering the final puzzle pieces
寻找最后一环线索
at the New York office of the D.E.A.
为什么是缉毒局
The drug enforcement agency, why?
那你得问他们了  警探
You'd have to ask them, detective.
好吧  不过我还得扣留你  知道吗
Okay. Well, I'm still gonna have to hold you, you know?
最多24小时
For up to 24 hours.
然后你们就不会再见到我了
And then you'll never see me again.
好的  多谢  比尔
All right. Thanks, Bill.
诺亚的不在场证明可靠
Well, Noah's alibi is solid.
他不是凶手
He's definitely not the killer.
但我们要相信他缉毒局那一套说辞吗
But do we believe his story about the D.E.A.?
我是说  这个案子和毒品有什么关系
I mean, what does any of this have to do with drugs?
只有一种方法能查明
Well, there's only one way to find out.
莱恩  看看你能不能查出
Ryan, see if you can uncover
米歇尔在缉毒局做什么
what Michelle was doing at the D.E.A.
我会试试看  但现在太晚了
I'll try, but it's late.
明早前大概不会有什么消息
Probably won't hear anything till the morning.
今天就到这儿吧
Well, I guess we should call it a night.
好吧  卡塞尔  回见
Okay, Castle. See you later.
回见  我们可以一起回我家
Later? We can go back to my place together.
我要跟你前妻吃晚餐  记得吗
Um, I have a dinner date with your ex-wife, remember?
我记得
Yeah. I remember.
我只是希望你忘了
I was just hoping you'd forget.
不用等我了
Okay. Don't wait up.
我...
I...
亲爱的  拜托  放松
Oh, darling, please. Just relax.
我放松不下来  母亲
I can't relax, mother.
我的世界天旋地转
My--my worlds are colliding, okay?
我无法放松
I'm not-- I can't relax.
来杯酒吧  对我有用
Well, have a glass of wine. Works for me.
我打赌她们现在在外面
I bet there out there right now,
正聊着我的秘密呢
just telling secrets about me.
糟糕  我该怎么做
Boom. What do I do?
我该打给他们吗  我该打给他们
Should I call them? I should call them.
不不不
No, no, no.
你当初就不该
What you shouldn't have done
让梅瑞狄斯住下来
was let Meredith stay here in the first place.
这里可不是廉价旅馆  亲爱的
This isn't a flophouse, darling.
你不该再让吃白食的人留宿
You've got to stop letting freeloaders just live here.
母亲大人你这么说不觉得讽刺吗
Please tell me you see the irony.
天啊  梅瑞狄斯  卡塞尔做了什么
My god, Meredith. Castle did that?
我不敢相信你会嫁给他
I can't believe that you married him.
你不敢相信什么
What can't you believe?
什么  不  什么
What? No. What?
不  拜托
No. Come on.
贝克特  故事都有两面性
Beckett, there's two sides to that story.
你说了  什么故事  你告诉她什么了
That--what did you--what story--what did you tell her?
真相  理查德
The truth, Richard.
卡塞尔  你不是我以为我了解的那个人
Castle, you're not the man that I thought I knew.
我以前是
I'm the man you thought you knew.
现在也是  我以为你
I'm the man you know. I thought you--
我就是  你以为  我了解你
I'm that--you think-- I know you.
我就是他
I'm him.
这太没劲了
This is so not cool.
你说得对  他确实会向左倾
Oh, you're right. He does lean to the left.
说了吧  一紧张就这样
Told ya. Only when he's stressed.
我之前没发现
I've never even noticed that before.
什么  什么倾斜
What? D--what leans?
谢谢你  梅瑞狄斯  太有趣了
Thank you, Meredith. That was so fun.
谢谢你能来
Mm. Thanks for coming.
今晚很愉快  晚安  玛莎
You have a great night. Good night, Martha.
晚安  亲爱的
Good night, darling.
好吧  她说我什么了
Okay. What did she say about me?
拜托  我懂了  我懂了
Oh, come on. I get it. I get it.
这事我处理得不妥  对不起
I mishandled this whole thing, and I am sorry.
相信我  我很抱歉
Believe me, I am sorry.
求你告诉梅瑞狄斯说了什么
Please tell me what Meredith said.
说了什么我需要担心的吗
Is it anything I need to be worried about?
你知道吗  卡塞尔
You know what, Castle?
虽然继续折磨你很有趣
As much as fun as it would be to continue torturing you,
不过我现在更喜欢你了
I actually like you a little bit more now.
真的吗
You do?
是啊  梅瑞狄斯是个有趣
Mm-hmm. Yeah. Meredith is a fun,
充满活力  让人无法拒绝的女人
dynamic, and hard-to-say-no-to woman.
但是
But...
只要我们还在一起  她不能再住在这里了
as long as we're together, she never stays here again.
绝无异议
That goes without saying.
好吧
Okay.
转到语音信箱吧
Mm. Let it go to voice mail.
好的
Okay. Mm.
是分局打来的
Oh, it's the precinct.
-什么事  -贝克特
- What? - Beckett.
我刚刚联络了缉毒局的人
Hey, I just got off with the D.E.A.
你得尽快赶过来
You need to get down here right now.
我们马上就到
Yeah, okay. We'll be right there.
米歇尔对缉毒局的
Michelle was very interested
加勒比缉毒行动非常感兴趣
in the D.E.A.'s caribbean drug interdiction efforts,
这其中包括使用卫星照片
which involve the tracking of planes and boats
追踪飞机和船只
using satellite photos.
她拿到了三年前莉安娜·派珀
She obtained this 3-year-old satellite photo
被杀当晚的卫星照片
from the night of Leann Piper's murder.
瞧
Take a look.
有两艘船
There's two boats.
对  距离不超过50英尺
Yeah, less than 50 feet apart.
而且他们确认其中一艘是比利·派珀的
And they identified that one as Billy Piper's.
这就是他脱罪的方法
That's how he got away with it.
也是莉安娜的尸体没被发现的原因
That's why Leann was never found.
比利害怕她的尸体被冲上岸
Billy was afraid that her body would wash up,
所以他找了个同谋帮他把尸体
So he enlisted an accomplice to take the remains
扔到了没人能找到的地方
and dump them where nobody would ever look.
如果米歇尔知道了这件事
If Michelle got on to this,
那么那个同谋很可能就是杀害她的凶手
that accomplice might be the person who murdered her.
没错  但是她怎么知道去找另一艘船呢
Yeah, but how did she know to look for another boat?
那艘船最近被列为
It was recently listed as an asset
她离婚案的资产之一
in one of her divorce cases.
伙计们  你们绝对猜不到同谋是谁
And, guys, you're never gonna guess who the accomplice is.
你好  沃尔特
Hello, Walter.
找我有事吗
Can I help you?
是  我们因为一艘船来找一个人
Yeah, we're here to see a man about a boat.
我为什么要杀我前妻的离婚律师
Why would I kill my ex-wife's divorce lawyer?
她干得"好极"了
She did a terrible job.
就因为如此  我才赢了
And because of that, I won.
你想知道你为什么赢了吗
Do you want to know why you won?
因为米歇尔把所有的时间
Because Michelle was spending all of her time
花在筛查你近三年的财务政信息上
sifting through your financials from three years ago.
她很好奇你家
She became very interested in how your family
和比利·派珀家是怎么成为
and Billy Piper's family
同一家游艇俱乐部会员的
were all members of the same yacht club.
所以呢
So?
你和比利 Pier是朋友
You and Billy Piper were friends.
我再说一次  所以呢
Again, I respond, so?
所以
So...
米歇尔发现证据证明
Michelle found proof that you refueled your boat
你在比利妻子被害的水域加过油
near the waters where billy's wife was killed.
她用卫星图片追踪到你的船
She tracked your boat using satellite photos.
这是比利·派珀的船  也是他妻子最后被看到的地方
This is Billy Piper's boat, where his wife was last seen.
而这里是谁的船呢
And whose boat is this over here?
哦  是你的
Oh, it's yours.
缉毒局确认这是你的船
The D.E.A. identified it as your boat.
你是比利的同谋
You were Billy's accomplice.
你们的计划不错
The two of you had a pretty good plan,
但却有一件事没有料到
except for there was one thing you couldn't foresee.
那就是你妻子会雇米歇尔
That your wife would hire Michelle
代理她的离婚案
to represent her in your divorce.
米歇尔可能是在找外遇的证据
Michelle was probably looking for proof of an affair.
却发现了更严重的事情
Except she found something much worse.
去加勒比的那次航行
That little boat trip you took to the caribbean?
当她仔细调查
As she looked closer
和你在一起的人和你去的原因时
at who you were with and why you were there,
她就发现了真相
she discovered the truth.
我想和我的律师谈谈
I want to talk to my lawyer.
没有认罪  我们的案子也只是猜测
Without a confession, our case is purely speculative.
我们可以进一步调查沃尔特
Well, we could dig into Walter's life,
没准能找到证据
Maybe find some proof.
要是幸运还能找到动机
And some motive, too, if we're lucky.
看来觉得这事蹊跷的不只是我
Okay, so it's not just me?
沃尔特应该没什么真正的动机吧
Walter has no real motive, does he?
没有  但他为何要帮比利杀害他的妻子呢
No. I mean, why would walter help Billy kill his wife?
没错  他们是朋友  但沃尔特能得到什么呢
Yeah, sure, they're friends, but what was in it for Walter?
他们又不是达成一致互杀妻子
Well, it's not like they agreed to kill each others' wives,
就像《火车怪客》一样
like "Strangers on a Train."
但通过我们所看到沃尔特的夫妻关系
Though what we saw of... Walter's relationship,
我敢肯定他考虑过
I'm sure he thought about it.
伙计们
Hey, guys.
我在沃尔特的电话记录里发现了线索
I found something in Walter's phone records,
但我不确定这有什么用
and I'm not quite sure what to make of it.
在米歇尔遇害的当天早上
On the morning of Michelle's murder,
沃尔特给嘉瑞森家打了20分钟电话
Walter made a 20-minute phone call to the Garrison residence.
嘉瑞森  那个会计师
Garrison--the accountant
就是米歇尔迫不及待要见的人
that michelle was so desperate to meet?
沃尔特为什么给他打电话
Why would Walter call him?
这是谁
Who's this?
我的梦中情人
The woman of my dreams.
她嫁给了会计师
She's married to that accountant.
伙计们  看看比利的
Guys, look at Billy's...
亡妻
dead wife.
再看看会计师的妻子
And now look at the accountant's wife.
发型不同  鼻子不同  下巴不同  但是
Different hair, different nose, different chin, but...
她们是同一个女人
They're the same woman.
这就是为何他们没有发现尸体
That's why they never found a body,
因为比利的亡妻莉安娜
Because Billy's dead wife Leann...
还活着
is alive.
嘉瑞森太太  再一次感谢
Again, thank you, Mrs. Garrison
您能这么晚赶过来
for coming down here at such a late hour.
我丈夫不是已经回答过警探们所有的问题了吗
Didn't my husband answer all the other detectives' questions?
是的  但有一个问题
Oh, he did, but there was just one...
只有你能回答
that only you can answer.
这个女人是谁
Who's this woman?
来  我帮你拿
Oh, here. Let me get that for you.
-谢谢  -没事
- Thank you. - Yeah.
对不起  我不认识她
Sorry. I don't recognize her.
你确定吗
You sure about that?
你知道的
Because, you know,
名字可以改  相貌可以整
you can change your name, you can change your looks,
但有一点你改变不了
but there is one thing that you cannot change--
你的
Your...
指纹
fingerprints.
我们知道你是谁
We know who you are.
你好  莉安娜
Hello, Leann.
欢迎你死而复生
Welcome back from the dead.
我觉得你们一定认错人了
I think you must have the wrong person.
你可以歇歇了  莉安娜
You can drop the charade, Leann.
我们和你现任丈夫谈过了
We spoke with your current husband.
他说在米歇尔被害的当晚
He said that you drove into the city
你驱车进城
the night that Michelle was killed,
他也认出了凶器
and he also identified the murder weapon
是一把你们厨房丢失的
as a mahogany-handled ice pick
红木手柄的冰锥
missing from your kitchen.
说来真是可笑  一分钟前
You know, it's funny, for a minute there,
我们认为沃尔特是在帮助比利
We thought Walter was helping Billy.
但其实他是在帮助你
But actually, he was helping you.
但是我们想不出来原因是什么
The only thing that we couldn't figure out was why?
你为什么要如此大费周折
Why did you go through all of this?
因为每个人都喜欢比利
Because everybody loved Billy.
嫁给他你就会明白
You try being married to him.
他人前是个英雄  在家是个畜生
He was a hero in public and a monster at home.
当我终于有勇气和他离婚的时候
When I finally got the courage to divorce him,
你知道媒体怎么描述我
you know how the media portrayed me?
骗取一半财产的
As just another gold digging trophy wife,
拜金花瓶妻子
looking for her half.
他让我名誉扫地
He destroyed my reputation.
他还打算毁掉我
He was gonna destroy me.
唯一能让我重新开始的方法就是死
The only way I could get my life back was to die.
但你需要帮手
But you needed help.
而沃尔特需要钱
And Walter needed the money.
至少他当时需要
At least he did at the time.
于是我们拟定了计划
So we devised a plan.
我说服比利同意旅行
I convinced Billy to take the trip,
用威士忌把他灌醉睡着后
and then when the scotch put him to sleep...
你跑到了沃尔特的船上
You escaped on to Walter's boat,
将你的丈夫变成了杀妻凶手
turning your husband into a wife killer.
他活该有这下场
It's what he deserved.
我却得以重新开始
And I got to start over.
我应该去国外的
I was supposed to leave the country,
但我遇到了罗伯
but I met Rob, and...
我爱上了他
I fell for him.
我们在一起好开心
We were so happy.
直到米歇尔将种种线索联系在一起
Until Michelle put the pieces together.
她说她无法容忍法律下的不公正
She said she couldn't live with the injustice.
你们能相信这话吗  从律师口中说出来
I mean, can you believe that, from a lawyer?
她居然支持比利
She sided with Billy.
她知道他的为人
I mean, she knew what he was like.
她知道他对我的所作所为
She knew what he did to me.
她为什么不能睁只眼闭只眼呢
Why couldn't she just leave it alone?
站起来
Stand up.
快点  站起来
Let's go. Come on. Stand up.
转过身
Turn around.
双手放在后面
Hands behind your back.
莉安娜·派珀  你因谋杀米歇尔·图伊
Leann Piper, you are under arrest
而被逮捕
for the murder of Michelle Twohey.
我知道你的公寓可以住人了
I mean, I know your apartment is habitable again,
我只是...  你一定要走吗
I just... do you have to leave?
你想我留在这里  是真心不要我走
Do you want me here because you actually want me here
还是需要我保护你不受红发魔女的摧残
or do you need protection from the redheads?
两个原因都有
A little of both.
好的  这样吧
Okay, I'll tell you what.
如果你没办法应付了
If it gets to be too much,
你可以  来我家住
You can come and stay... at my place.
谢谢
Thank you.
我一个人去巴黎  不带上你
Are you sure it's okay that I'm going to Paris
真的可以吗
without you?
虽然我生病了  你也不应该错过啊
Just because I'm sick, you shouldn't miss it.
我要你去
I want you to go.
我们都是这样想
We all do.
现在什么情况
What's going on?
我只是感觉好内疚
I just feel so guilty
因为我生病害妈妈错过了假期
that mom is missing her vacation because I'm sick,
所以我让她替我们两个好好去玩
so I told her to enjoy Paris for the both of us.
你确定吗  阿丽克西斯  你妈妈...
Oh, are you sure, Alexis? I mean, your mother...
应该
Should...
享受她的假期
Enjoy her vacation.
一路平安  梅瑞德斯
Have a safe trip, Meredith.
我爱你  妈妈
Je t'aime, maman.
我也爱你
Moi aussi. Je t'aime.
拜拜了您呐  玩得开心
Adios, dear. Have fun.
再见  玛莎
Martha.
这几天真是...  糟糕
Well, this has been... oh, shoot.
我把皮包落在楼上了  帮帮忙吧
I left my purse upstairs. Be a dear.
我去拿
I'll grab it.
贝克特探长  认识你真是太开心了
Detective Beckett, it was a real pleasure.
是  的确是的
Yes, it really was.
知道吗  梅瑞狄斯  说来好笑
You know, Meredith, it's so funny.
当你最初过来坚持住在这里时
When you first came and insisted on staying here,
我还担心你是不是有什么不可告人的目的
I was afraid that you might have had a secret agenda.
事实上  我有
Actually, I did.
阿丽克西斯告诉了我你俩的事
When Alexis told me about you two
以及你们是来真的
and how this one was serious,
我就想着要自己来证实一下
I knew I had to check it out for myself.
我很高兴我这样做了
And I'm so glad I did.
你们真是天造地设的一对
You two are great together.
谢谢
Thank you.
我可以问个问题吗
Can I ask you a question?
你和里克为什么会分手
Why didn't it work out between you and Rick?
抱歉
I'm sorry.
这个问题太隐私了
Is that too personal?
不不  没事
Oh, no, no, no. It's fine.
和理查德的婚姻生活是很幸福的
You know, being married to Richard was great--
浪漫与刺激不断
Full of romance and excitement,
感觉如同可口的蛋奶酥
Like a deliciously sweet souffle.
然而有一天  我意识到  他了解了我的一切
And then one day, I realized, he knew everything about me--
我最隐私的秘密  我最不可告人的伤痛
My deepest secrets, my worst pain--
了解到足以写无数小说
Enough to fill a million novels.
而我对他的了解
But I didn't know enough about him
连本小册子都写不出来
to even write a pamphlet.
我不明白
I don't understand.
比如说  每次我问他
For instance, whenever I asked him about
从来不知道自己父亲是谁有何感受
how he felt about never knowing his father,
他就会假笑
He would smirk.
你也知道他假笑的样子
You know the way he smirks.
然后他就会说句俏皮话
And then he would throw out a quip
改变话题
and change the subject.
我们的婚姻有不足  而我不愿意将就
Our marriage went one way, and that wasn't enough for me.
我意思是
I mean...
蛋奶酥很美味
Souffles are wonderful,
但顶上那层塌下来是迟早的事
but sooner or later, they always fall.
但那是很久以前的事了
Oh, but that was a long, long time ago.
应该有15年了吧
Wh-what? 15 years in fact.
他现在完全不同了
He's a totally different man now.
当然了
Yes, of course.
我只是好奇问下
I was just curious.
好了  拿来了
Okay. Here we go.
你最好了  里克  谢谢
Oh, you are the best, Rick. Thank you.
那是自然
You bet.
希望可以再见到你
I hope we see each other again.
我也希望  梅瑞德斯  旅行愉快
Oh, me, too, Meredith. Have a wonderful trip.
再见  里克
Good-bye, Rick.
拜
Bye.
在你走之前  我给你做早餐吧
How about I make you a little breakfast before you leave?
我很快给你做个早全餐
I'm gonna whip you up a smor-let.
听着比尝起来感觉好
It sounds better than it tastes.
等等  不对  应该是尝起来比听着感觉好
Wait, that's--no. It's the other way around.